Rajesh Kumar

Website http://faculty.uestc.edu.cn/KUMARRAJESH/

Phone No: +86-13699029542

Email: rajakumarlohano@gmail.com

Nationality: Pakistan
Gender: Male
Marital Status: Single
WeChat #: raja21066
Google Scholar: Click Here



PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Dr. Rajesh Kumar is an outstanding graduate of the University of Electronic Science and Technology of China. He won the academic performance award and outstanding graduate student at the University of Electronic Science and Technology of China from 2016 to 2019. He worked on two national projects with prof Xiaosong Zhang during 2017-2019 (including the 2019 National Natural Science Foundation Fund "Research on Intelligent Identification Method of IoT Malware Based on Android"). Additionally, he won the project "Blockchain Based Secure Data Sharing" from the University of Electronic Science and Technology Talent Special Fund in 2019. He has published more than 35 International Journal and Conference papers in the field of Deep Learning, Machine Learning, and Information Security. He has received government and university level projects in 2019 and 2020.



RESEARCH INTERESTS

• Network Security • Deep Learning • Machine Learning • Computer Vision • Blockchain technology



EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF ELECTRONICS SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY OF CHINA PHD (Computer Science)	2016-2019
UNIVERSITY OF SINDH, JAMSHORO MS (Computer Science)	2014-2016
UNIVERSITY OF SINDH, JAMSHORO BS (Computer Science)	2010-2013



EMPLOYMENT

YANGZI DELTA RIVER RESEACH INSTITUTE OF HUZHOU, UNIVERSITY OF

ELECTRONICS SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY OF CHINA

July 2021- Current

Associate Professor

UNIVERSITY OF ELECTRONICS SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY OF CHINA

Advisor: Dr. Wang Wenyong

Postdoctoral Fellow

June 2019- June 2021

LIST OF SCI JOURNALS

S#	Tittle	Author Order	Journal Name	Date	Cit ati on	Impact Factor
1	Blockchain-federated-learning and deep learning models for covid-19 detection using ct imaging.	1	IEEE SENSORS JOURNAL	15-07- 2021	99	3.07
2	An integration of blockchain and ai for secure data sharing and detection of ct images for the hospitals	1	Computerized Medical Imaging and Graphics	01-01- 2021	35	3.75
3	Research on data mining of permission-induced risk for android iot devices.	1	Applied Sciences- Basel	2-1-2019	26	2.47
4	A multimodal malware detection technique for android iot devices using various features	1	IEEE ACCESS	23-05- 2019	62	3.74
5	An online semantic-enhanced graphical model for evolving short text stream clustering	4	IEEE Transactions on Cybernetics	30-09- 2021	1	11.44
6	Secure large-scale e-voting system based on blockchain contract using a hybrid consensus model combined with sharding	2	ETRI journal	01-04- 2021	11	1.09
7	A federated learning approach for privacy protection in context-aware recommender systems	2	Computer Journal (Oxford Press)	30-04- 2021	3	1.07
8	Making assembly line in supply chain robust and secure using UHF RFID	2	Scientific Reports	10-09- 2021	5	3.99
9	An efficient and provably secure ecc-based conditional privacy-preserving authentication for vehicle-to-vehicle communication in vanets	4	IEEE Transactions on Vehicular Technology	13-01- 2021	9	5.37
10	Visual features with spatio-temporal-based fusion model for cross-dataset vehicle re-identification	5	Applied Sciences- Basel	01-08- 2020	6	2.47
11	Adaptive wavelet based mri brain image de-noising	3	Frontiers in Neuroscience	22-08- 2020	21	3.70
12	Efficient hybrid clustering scheme for data delivery using internet of things enabled vehicular ad hoc networks in smart city traffic congestion.	6	Journal of Internet Technology	1-12- 2020	7	0.78
13	Efficient and deep vehicle re-identification using multi-level feature extraction	6	Applied Sciences- Basel	27-03- 2019	13	2.47
14	An adaptive multi-layer botnet detection technique using machine learning classifiers	3	Applied Sciences- Basel	11-06- 2019	82	2.47
15	Context-aware bidirectional neural model for sindhi named entity recognition	4	Applied Sciences- Basel	28-09- 2021	-	2.67
16	Trends in vehicle re-identification past, present, and future: a comprehensive review	5	Mathematics	27-11- 2021	-	2.25
17	Multi scale and direction target detecting in remote sensing images via modified YOLO-v4	3	IEEE Journal of Selected Topics in Applied Earth Observations and Remote Sensing	01-06- 2022	-	3.78

LIST OF BOOK CHAPTERS

S#	Tittle	Author Order	Book Name
1	A survey of intelligent techniques for android malware detection	1	Malware Analysis Using Artificial Intelligence and Deep Learning (Spinger)

LIST OF EI JOURNALS

S#	Tittle	Author Order	Journal Name	Date	Citation
1	Simple and efficient computational intelligence strategies for effective collaborative decisions	2	Future Internet	21-01- 2019	-
2	Analysis of resnet and googlenet models for malware detection	3	Journal of Computer Virology and Hacking Techniques	28-09- 2018	98
3	Optimizing a deep learning model in order to have a robust neural network topology	2	International Journal of Modeling and Optimization	1-06- 2018	1
4	Modelling choice selection system of a public sector general university in pakistan	1	Sindh University Research Journal-SURJ (2016)	1-08- 2016	1

LIST OF CONFERENCES

S#	Tittle	Author Order	Journal Name	Date	Citation
1	A survey of blockchain based on e-voting systems	2	Proceedings of the 2019 2nd International Conference on Blockchain Technology and Applications	09-12- 2019	17
2	Malicious code detection based on image processing using deep learning	1	International Conference on Computing and Artificial Intelligence (ICCAI 2018)"		42
3	Effective and explainable detection of android malware based on machine learning algorithms	1	International Conference on Computing and Artificial Intelligence (ICCAI 2018)	12-03- 2018	18
4	Malicious URL detection using multi-layer filtering model	1	The 14th International Computer Conference on Wavelet Active Media Technology and Information Processing (2017)	12-02- 2018	14
5	Evaluating the performance of deep neural networks for health decision making	3	8th International Congress of Information and Communication Technology (ICICT-2018)	27-01- 2018	10
6	Probabilistic time context framework for big data collaborative recommendation	4	International Conference on Computing and Artificial Intelligence (ICCAI 2018)	12-03- 2018	2
7	Evaluating the performance of resnet model based on image recognition	3	International Conference on Computing and Artificial Intelligence (ICCAI 2018)	12-03- 2018	33
8	Analysis of resnet model for malicious code detection	3	The 14th International Computer Conference on Wavelet Active	02-07- 2017	4

			Media Technology and Information Processing (2017)		
9	Internet of things—smart traffic management system for smart cities using big data analytics	The 14th International Computer Conference on Wavelet Active Media Technology and Information Processing (2017)		02-07- 2017	38
10	A hybrid technique to detect botnets, based on p2p traffic similarity	2	2 2019 Cybersecurity and Cyberforensics Conference (CCC)		13
11	An improved convolutional neural network model for intrusion detection in networks	4	2019 Cybersecurity and Cyberforensics Conference (CCC)	07-05- 2019	35
12	Elimination of irrelevant features and heart disease recognition by employing machine learning algorithms using clinical data	5	The 17th International Computer Conference on Wavelet Active Media Technology and Information Processing (2020)	18-12- 2020	-
13	H3DNN: 3d deep learning based detection of covid-19 virus using lungs computed tomography	3	The 17th International Computer Conference on Wavelet Active Media Technology and Information Processing (2020)	18-12- 2020	7
14	A Non-Parametric Multi-Lingual Clustering Model for Temporal Short Text	The 17th International Computer Conference on Wavelet Active Media Technology and Information Processing (2020)		18-12- 2020	2
15	Neural Joint Model for Part-of-Speech Tagging and Entity Extraction	2	13th International Conference on Machine Learning and Computing (2021)	26-02- 2021	-
16	Blockchain Based Monitoring on Trustless Supply Chain Processes	3	6th International Conference on Cloud Computing and Big Data Analytics (2021)	24-04- 2021	-
17	Analyzing and battling the emerging variants of covid-19 using artificial neural network and blockchain	6	The 18th International Computer Conference on Wavelet Active Media Technology and Information Processing (2021)	10-12- 2021	



PROJECTS

S#	Project Name	Date	Project Number	Project Source
1	Research on Blockchain Sharding Consensus (区块链分片共识研究)	2019/07 2021/07	Y030190236010 16201	China Postdoctoral Science Foundation
2	AI pattern recognition and COVID-19 blockchain security data sharing	2020/07 2021/07	Y125190285540 16524	University of Electronic Science and Technology of China
3	Research on Airline Passenger Luggage Tracing Technology Based on Electronic Tag 我们自然科学基金项目:基于电子标签的航空旅客行李全程跟踪技术研究	2021/01 2024/12	U2033212	National Natural Science Foundation of China
4	Research on Intelligent Identification Method of IoT Malware Based on Android 基于 Android 的 IoT 恶意软件智能识别方法研究	2017/01 2019/07	61572115	National Natural Science Foundation of China



& SKILLS

Leadership & Management Skills:

- ✓ Supervision of a Master's student for design projects for National Science Foundation of China.
- ✓ Led a team of data sharing security towards the Kaggle competition
- ✓ Organized weekly training with team-based challenges.
- ✓ Presented challenge solutions.

Programming Language Skills: • JAVA • C/C++, • Python, • Android • DotNet • PHP

Database Design Skills: Databases and Database Management of Enterprise Organization University of Sindh.

Computer Skills: Microsoft Office, Visual Studio, MYSQL, Adobe Photoshop

Advising and collaboration of Master's students:

- ✓ Binary Analysis Tool For Identification Variable Types In Binary Programs.
- ✓ Detecting Privacy Leaks Through Existing Android Frameworks.

CERTIFICATES

University of Electronic Science & Technology of China <u>Best Performance Award</u> , <u>China</u>	2018
Aims Academy, Pakistan Microsoft Office	April 2011 to Aug 2011
University of Sindh, Pakistan Web Developer	1 year
NETLYNIC I.T ACADEMY, Pakistan Java, Android, Developer	Jan 2011 to JAN 2013

Real Time Project Development

Python Development:

- ✓ Blockchain based federated learning model for secure data sharing (Code).
- ✓ Federated learning for medical images (Code).
- ✓ Design a federated learning model for secure data sharing (Code).
- ✓ Android malware detection (Code).
- ✓ Cancer detection (Code).

Web Development:

- ✓ University of Sindh examination results.(Code) (http://exam.usindh.edu.pk/).
- ✓ University of Sindh admission results. (Code) (http://admission.usindh.edu.pk/).
- ✓ Book board website (http://www.stbb.edu.pk).
- ✓ Time table management system (http://timetable.usindh.edu.pk).
- ✓ School management system.

Android Development:

- ✓ SMS and call tracking system (Code).
- ✓ Online banking system (Code).
- ✓ Result information system using sms technology.
- ✓ Excel sms sender (Bulk SMS Sender).
- ✓ Puzzle game (Code).

- ✓ Annoying alarm system.
- ✓ Event notification system University of Sindh.
- ✓ Fees Payment System.

Java Development

- ✓ RFID based attendance management system.
- ✓ School management system (<u>Code</u>) (The Guardian School Hyderabad) .
- ✓ Laboratory management system (<u>Code</u>)(Advance Lab Hyderabad).

.Net Development

- ✓ Hospital management system.
- ✓ Shop management system.

Arduino Development

✓ Factory control using ethernet (Internet Technology).

Note: All projects source code available this link: https://github.com/raja21068/



PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES

Journal External Reviewer:

- ✓ IEEE Transactions on Information Forensics and Security.
- ✓ IEEE Internet of Things.
- ✓ Elsevier Computers & Security.
- ✓ IEEE ACCESS.

Conference External Reviewer:

- ✓ The 14th International Computer Conference on Wavelet Active Media Technology and Information Processing.
- ✓ The 15th International Computer Conference on Wavelet Active Media Technology and Information Processing.
- ✓ 2st Workshop on Cloud Security and Privacy.



TALKS

- ✓ Key Note Speaker: Challenges and Implications of blockchain with federated learning, "in Gundong 2019".
- ✓ Presenter: Malicious Code Detection: Image Processing Using Deep Learning: International Conference on Computing and Artificial Intelligence (ICAAI), Chengdu, China, March 2018.
- ✓ **Presenter:** Artificial Intelligence challenges and implantation to the current trends, AI Seminar in UESTC, 2019.
- ✓ **Presenter:** Latex and other research tools: Invited talk at Sichuan University.



PERSONAL INFORMATION

Languages Chinese, English, Sindhi & Urdu.

Hobbies Watching Movies , Badminton, Table Tennis, Swimming, Books Reading & Jogging.